<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HTB on Jordan&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/blog/htb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HTB on Jordan&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2025, Jordan Galida.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jordangalida.github.io/blog/htb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HTB Blackfield Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-blackfield-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-blackfield-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box starts off with gaining access to an account via ASREPRoasting. This account then has permissions to &lt;code&gt;ForceChangePassword&lt;/code&gt; over another account which has access to an SMB share that contains data from what looks to be a recent forensic audit on the company. This share contains a dump of LSASS, in which we find an NT hash for a user with the ability to remote into the host. After remoting in, we discover our user is a part of the &lt;code&gt;Backup Operators&lt;/code&gt; group. We are able to create a copy of NTDS.dit, transfer it over to our attack host, and dump the hashes allowing us to compromise the Administrator.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Hospital Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-hospital-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-hospital-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box starts out with a a strange &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; scan that shows both Windows and Linux, which we later find out that there is a Linux VM running on a Windows box. We find a file upload vulnerability, but only one type of PHP file extension executes code, and a lot of the execution functions are blocked. Eventually we find one that works, and gain initial access. We use the &lt;code&gt;GameOverlay&lt;/code&gt; exploit to escalate permissions to root and crack the &lt;code&gt;drwilliams&lt;/code&gt; user&amp;rsquo;s password from &lt;code&gt;/etc/shadow&lt;/code&gt;. We then log into the &lt;code&gt;roundcube&lt;/code&gt; instance we found in the beginning and find an email from a &lt;code&gt;drbrown&lt;/code&gt; requesting an &lt;code&gt;eps&lt;/code&gt; file for &lt;code&gt;GhostScript&lt;/code&gt;. We are able to create a malicious file that spawns a reverse shell and gain access to the Windows host. There are multiple ways to get admin access, but we notice that there is some script running to enter the admin&amp;rsquo;s credentials into the &lt;code&gt;roundcube&lt;/code&gt; instance so we use &lt;code&gt;mimikatz&lt;/code&gt; to dump credentials from the credential manager.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB LogForge Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-logforge-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-logforge-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box starts off with a filtered FTP port and a very bare website that we discover is Apache Tomcat. Attempting to access the &lt;code&gt;manager&lt;/code&gt; page is blocked, but we are able to use a parsing bypass to gain access and log in with very weak credentials. After logging in, we discover that there is an endpoint vulnerable to &lt;code&gt;Log4Shell&lt;/code&gt; which we are able to exploit to gain initial access. I completed this box in March 2025, and exploiting &lt;code&gt;Log4Shell&lt;/code&gt; was the most difficult part due to having to use older versions and work-arounds to get everything to work correctly. After gaining initial access, we find out that the FTP server contains the root flag and is blocking access via a cronjob that runs a &lt;code&gt;jar&lt;/code&gt; file. We are able to download this Java program offline, reverse engineer it, and figure out that the FTP credentials are environment variables. We are able to utilize the original &lt;code&gt;Log4Shell&lt;/code&gt; vulnerability to extract these credentials, log into FTP and grab the root flag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Agile Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-agile-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-agile-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box was a bit more difficult than past ones I have done in this CPTS playlist. This is mainly due to the complex interconnected parts of the Python web application. We start off by finding a local file disclosure vulnerability&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We start off by running an &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; scan with scripting enabled, and version detection on all ports&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-console&#34; data-lang=&#34;console&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;$sudo nmap -sC -sV -p- 10.10.11.203 -oA Scans/&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Starting Nmap 7.94SVN ( https://nmap.org ) at 2025-03-13 18:42 EDT&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Nmap scan report for 10.10.11.203&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Host is up (0.021s latency).&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Not shown: 65533 closed tcp ports (reset)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;PORT   STATE SERVICE VERSION&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;22/tcp open  ssh     OpenSSH 8.9p1 Ubuntu 3ubuntu0.1 (Ubuntu Linux; protocol 2.0)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;| ssh-hostkey:&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;|   256 f4:bc:ee:21:d7:1f:1a:a2:65:72:21:2d:5b:a6:f7:00 (ECDSA)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;|_  256 65:c1:48:0d:88:cb:b9:75:a0:2c:a5:e6:37:7e:51:06 (ED25519)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;80/tcp open  http    nginx 1.18.0 (Ubuntu)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;|_http-title: Did not follow redirect to http://superpass.htb&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;|_http-server-header: nginx/1.18.0 (Ubuntu)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Service Info: OS: Linux; CPE: cpe:/o:linux:linux_kernel&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Service detection performed. Please report any incorrect results at https://nmap.org/submit/ .&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Nmap done: 1 IP address (1 host up) scanned in 19.54 seconds&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only two ports are open - HTTP and SSH. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the webserver. Immediately, the IP is changed to &lt;code&gt;http://superpass.htb/&lt;/code&gt;, so we update our &lt;code&gt;/etc/hosts&lt;/code&gt; to reflect that. We refresh the page and it resolves&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jordangalida.github.io/images/Agile/website.png&#34; alt=&#34;Website&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Pressed Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-pressed-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-pressed-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box starts off by finding a WordPress instance that leaks a backup of &lt;code&gt;wp-config&lt;/code&gt; which includes admin credentials. There is also a file disclosure vulnerability in one of the plugins, which you could get the &lt;code&gt;wp-config&lt;/code&gt; that way also. Attempting to log into WordPress is prevented by a MFA plugin. Instead, we are able to utilize XML-RPC to interact with the instance and gain initial access by creating a web shell. There are strict firewall rules in place to block you from obtaining a reverse shell, so everything must be done through the web shell or a forward-shell. We find a &lt;code&gt;pkexec&lt;/code&gt; version on the machine that is vulnerable to &lt;a href=&#34;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2021-4034&#34;&gt;CVE-2021-4034&lt;/a&gt;, which we are able to exploit to gain root access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Manager Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-manager-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-manager-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box was a bit annoying due to one assumption the creator made during the initial access phase. The box starts off with the &lt;code&gt;nmap&lt;/code&gt; scans clearly showing that is is a domain controller with all of the expected services running. We are able to enumerate users via a RID cycling attack, and (this is the annoying part) we eventually identify an account using their username as their password via a password spraying attack. After gaining initial access, we discover that Active Directory Certificate Services is present and identify a privilege escalation vulnerability, &lt;code&gt;ESC7&lt;/code&gt;, which we use to get admin access and obtain the root flag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Outdated Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-outdated-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-outdated-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box starts off with an initial access vector that requires a decent amount of research and customization. We find an open SMB share with a PDF about recent vulnerabilities that have been identified within the organization and an email address to send any knowledge of new vulnerabilities found. One of the CVEs there is Follina, which is a remote code execution vulnerability that results from a malicious word document. However, sending a URL with a word document, doesn&amp;rsquo;t go through for whatever reason. Using John Hammond&amp;rsquo;s Follina exploit, you can get this to work without having to do a work-around on your end. We land on a nested VM, as the &lt;code&gt;btables&lt;/code&gt; user who is a member of the &lt;code&gt;ITStaff&lt;/code&gt; group and can create Shadow Credentials for the &lt;code&gt;sflowers&lt;/code&gt; user. After moving laterally to the &lt;code&gt;sflowers&lt;/code&gt; user, we are able to exploit WSUS to get a shell as SYSTEM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Shoppy Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-shoppy-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-shoppy-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shoppy starts off with discovering a simple website that shows a countdown until launch. Upon further enumeration, we find a login portal which is vulnerable to NoSQL injection due to the application running on NodeJS. We use this vulnerability to obtain credentials for a user. After performing subdomain enumeration with a bunch of different wordlists, we find the &lt;code&gt;mattermost&lt;/code&gt; subdomain. We then are able to use the credentials we discovered earlier to log in and find a chat with cleartext credentials for a user on the host. After we SSH into the box, we find that we have &lt;code&gt;sudo&lt;/code&gt; permissions to run a home-grown password-manager application which requests a master password. By running &lt;code&gt;strings&lt;/code&gt; with different encodings, we find the master password and the password-manager application gives us credentials for another user. The new user is a member of the &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; group which allows us to spin up a container and mount the entire host file system giving us access to the &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; user&amp;rsquo;s directory and the final flag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Trick Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-trick-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-trick-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this box, we start out using a zone transfer to find a new subdomain that leads us to third party payroll software which is vulnerable to unauthenticated SQL injection. We then use this SQL injection to read local files and eventually identify a user on the system as well as another subdomain that is vulnerable to LFI. We are able to leverage the LFI to read the SSH private key of the user we identified and gain initial access. Upon establishing a foothold, we find that we are a part of a group that has the ability to restart &lt;code&gt;fail2ban&lt;/code&gt; as well as edit the &lt;code&gt;action.d&lt;/code&gt; directory. We use this to elevate our privileges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Driver Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-driver-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-driver-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box starts off with a website where you can upload printer drivers, which is a hint to a known critical vulnerability that happened pretty recently. The website says that anything uploaded will be reviewed by someone. In order to gain initial access, you need to upload a file that will execute when viewed such as a &lt;code&gt;.scf&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.lnk&lt;/code&gt; file that reaches out to an SMB server that we control while running a tool like &lt;code&gt;Responder&lt;/code&gt;. This allows you to catch an NTLMv2 hash that can be cracked to gain access as the user Tony. To escalate privileges, you exploit the &lt;code&gt;PrintNightmare&lt;/code&gt; vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Access Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-access-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-access-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box starts out with a WordPress plugin vulnerability that allows for unauthenticated SQL injection. After logging in as the manager user, you find out that this version of WordPress is vulnerable to an XML parsing issue in the media library that leads to an XXE vulnerability. You use this vulnerability to read the wp-config file that has credentials for the FTP user which in turn contains a file that has a user&amp;rsquo;s credentials. You log into the box as the user, and find that a password manager named passpie is being used and contains the root user&amp;rsquo;s credentials. The passpie hidden directory contains a PGP private key which you are able to decrypt and export root&amp;rsquo;s password.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Access Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-access-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-access-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this box, you find an open FTP port that allows for anonymous login and exposes two files: a Microsoft Access database file and a zip file. The database file contains the credentials to unzip the zip file. The zip file contains a .pst file that has an email with credentials allowing you to telnet into the machine. On the host, you find a third party application that runs cmdkey and saves the administrator&amp;rsquo;s credentials. We then use the saved credentials to establish a reverse shell as the administrator user.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Remote Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-remote-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-remote-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a pretty straight-foward box, however you&amp;rsquo;re going to have to do some Googling to figure out the location where you may find credentials. They are not in the normal expected places. After gaining access to the CMS, you need to again Google version numbers. Checking for public exploits is the first thing I usually do in the real world, but not top on my list for HTB (I should still do this). After exploiting an RCE in the CMS, you gain initial access. You discover that the service account is running the common SeImpersonatePrivilege, which allows you to use the PrintSpoofer exploit to get a shell as SYSTEM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Delivery Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-delivery-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-delivery-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this box, you find a ticketing support application that discloses a valid internal email address. This address can then be used to register your own valid company email address that allows you to access an internal chat application which discloses credentials to a user on the host. You are then able to SSH in as this user and identify credentials stored in a config file that gives you access to a MySQL database with the password hash for the root account. You must utilize a clue found previously in the internal chat application to crack the hash.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Active Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-active-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-active-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This box is pure Active Directory. In this box, you are able to find a password in a Group Policy file that can be decrypted which gives you access to a service account. You can then use the service account to kerberoast the Administrator account.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always, we start out with two nmap scans. One for the top ports and one for all ports with scripts enabled and version detection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Soccer Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-soccer-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-soccer-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Soccer is box that cycles through enumeration and exploitation which is very similar to real-word pentesting. In this box, you exploit a file upload vulnerability that gives you an initial shell only to find another virtual host. After identifying that WebSockets are being used, you find a SQL injection vulnerability which results in credentials for a user on the box. Finally, you find a SETUID bit set that allows you to run another program which is able to run a python script, eventually resulting in a root shell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Union Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-union-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-union-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Union is a box that is heavily focused on, you guessed in, UNION-based SQL injection. This box was a little difficult to find the initial injection because you almost have to know a valid player&amp;rsquo;s name, or guess that the table is named &amp;ldquo;players&amp;rdquo;. Without those, you would get the same result each time essentially masking the SQL injection. Additionally, SQLMap is blocked.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As always, starting off with our nmap scans, we do a quick and comprehensive scan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB Forest Write-up</title>
      <link>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-forest-write-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jordangalida.github.io/htb-forest-write-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Forest machine is a unique box due to it being entirely Active Directory. I agree with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=H9FcE_FMZio&#34;&gt;IppSec&lt;/a&gt; that this box should probably be rated medium rather than easy. However, I think this is a great box to practice your Active Directory enumeration skills and really dig into using BloodHound to find specific attack paths. There is a funky aspect of this box in which a script is being run to reset your user&amp;rsquo;s privileges, and this causes some weird problems you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally have.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
